Elvin Mark Munoz Vega

▼ Tokyo, Japan ☑ munoz.vega.em@gmail.com **** +8108089430187

in elvin-mark-munoz-vega nelvin-mark

About Me

I'm a passionate software developer with a strong interest on AI and machine learning. I've been working in the field for about 3 years and have a solid foundation in Go, Python and Java using multiple frameworks such as FastAPI, Flask and SpringBoot to build restful APIs for Backend applications.

My expertise lies in natural language processing and computer vision. I'm driven by a desire to create innovative solutions that make a positive impact.

Education

BS March 2011 - April 2016 **National University of Engineering | Lima, Peru**, Engineering Physics Osaka University - Center for Japanese Language and Culture | Osaka, Japan, April 2017 - March 2018 Japanese Language

BS Tokyo Institute of Technology | Tokyo, Japan, Computer Science April 2018 – March 2022

Experience _

UTEC (Universidad de Ingeniería y Tecnología), Researcher

Lima, Peru April 2016 - March 2017

- Developed software in C++ for controlling an optical setup to manipulate microrobots by creating and controlling convection flows.
- · Utilized the Artificial Potential method to improve microrobot control and enable obstacle avoidance.

Tokyo Institute of Technology, Researcher

- Tokyo, Japan April 2021 - March 2022 · Successfully trained neural networks using SAM optimization and assessed their performance.
- Studied the impact of hyperparameters on training outcomes.
- Investigated loss landscapes and parameter trajectories using the Digits dataset.
- Utilized the Weights and Biases platform for tracking training progress.
- Leveraged GPU clusters provided by the university lab for efficient training.

Rakuten Mobile, Software Developer

- · Developed and tested scalable microservices in Go, integrating with NoSQL and relational databases, with robust CI/CD pipelines and containerized deployments
- Designed and implemented API backends leveraging modern backend frameworks, integrating with cloud services for authentication, email, storage, and database management.
- Analyzed and enhanced third-party software by documenting and modifying opensource components, ensuring alignment with project requirements.
- Built and optimized high-performance communication modules for internal systems, focusing on concurrency, scalability, and system reliability

Tokyo, Japan April 2022 - Present

Publications

Exploiting the transient behavior of thermocapillary convection flows to enhance non-contact mesoscale manipulation

Quispe, Johan and Muñoz, Elvin and Vela, Emir

2016

10.1063/1.4963159

Optimizing the speed of single infrared-laser-induced thermocapillary flows micromanipulation by using design of experiments

2017

Muñoz, Elvin and Quispe, Johan and Lambert, Pierre and Bolopion, Aude Terrazas, Ronald and Régnier, Stéphane and Vela, Emir

10.1007/s12213-017-0097-3 🗹

Single particle manipulation/sorting through the transient response of thermocapillary convection flows

2016

J. E. Quispe and J. C. Inga and E. M. Muñoz and S. Régnier and E. Vela

10.1109/MARSS.2016.7561730 🗹

Closed-loop selective manipulation of multiple microparticles by controlling the transient regime of Marangoni flows

2016

E. M. Muñoz and J. E. Quispe and E. Vela

10.1109/IROS.2016.7759754 🗹

Laser-induced thermocapillary flow manipulation of microparticles with obstacle avoidance in a non-patterned fluidic environment

2017

E. M. Muñoz and J. E. Quispe and S. Régnier and E. Vela

10.1109/MARSS.2017.8001939 🗹

Hand rehabilitation using Soft-Robotics

2016

A. A. Reymundo and E. M. Muñoz and M. Navarro and E. Vela and H. I. Krebs

10.1109/BIOROB.2016.7523708

Projects _____

PyTorch Simple Trainer

 Developed a tool that will allow you to train any computer vision model against custom datasets. github.com/elvinmark/pytorch_trainer ☑

JADE

• Built a simple framework to build and train neural networks in Java. This framework was written from scratch so no extra dependencies are needed.

github.com/elvinmark/jade **ど**

Learning Korean App

• Built a simple web application in Angular that helps beginners learn the Korean language through flashcards and short quizzes.

github.com/elvinmark/korean-learning-app

Movie Recommender

• Built a simple movie recommender that leverages a lightweight text embedding deep learning model to search for similar movies from a clustered movie list.

github.com/elvin-mark/movie-recommender

Technologies _____

Languages: Python, C, Java, Go, SQL, JavaScript **Technologies:** Git, Jenkins, Docker, K8s, AWS